Preliminary Guide to the Round Table on Science and Public Affairs Records, 1973 - 1983 UA.24.01.0002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Round Table on Science and Public Affairs records
1973 - 1983
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Graduate School
UA.24.01.0002
9 Linear Feet
The Round Table on Science and Public Affairs, sponsored by the Duke University Graduate School, began in 1973. The program invited speakers to discuss issues of science, technology, and public policy, and their relationships to academics, industry, and government. The collection includes cassettes and reel-to-reel tapes of speeches, correspondence, financial documents, brochures, announcements, lists of seminar attendees, travel vouchers, clippings, and other materials. Major subjects include technology, science, public policy, and the effect of technology on social and public policy. English.
9000 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Round Table on Science and Public Affairs Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1977 (A77-157) and 1983 (A83-60).
Historical Note
The Round Table on Science and Public Affairs was sponsored by the Graduate School, under the general direction of Dean John C. McKinney. Planning began in late 1973 in conjunction with the appointment of William Bevan to the faculty. Dr. Bevan became the director of the program. Its goals were to acquaint scientists and engineers in academia with their counterparts in industry and government, to help prepare scientists and engineers for careers in public service, and to foster understanding on the part of the academic community and the general public of the roles and uses of science and technology. The program brought in speakers to discuss problems of science and public policy. Subjects included Technology, Law, and Privacy, the National Science Foundation, Nuclear Energy, Exchange Programs, Social Accountability and Educational Testing, and Science in Latin America. Dr. Bevan directed the program until 1983, when it appears to have ceased operation for a time. Lectures were presented under its auspices in January 1989 and March 1990.
Collection Overview
The collection includes sound recordings, correspondence, financial documents, brochures, announcements, lists of seminar attendees, travel vouchers, clippings, and other materials. The first series, Sound Recordings, consists of three boxes of reel-to-reel and cassette tapes of roundtable sessions. The Subject Files series is comprised of printed materials, arranged in reverse chronological order. A year's set of files typically includes correspondence with speakers, accounting records, brochures, fellowship and miscellaneous information.
Related Material
Graduate School records
Duke University Archives
Industry and education; Higher education and state; Audiocassettes; Public policy -- United States.; Science and industry -- United States; Sound recordings; Technology and social change; Technology transfer; Duke University. Graduate School; Duke University. Graduate School
- Sound Recordings
  Scope and Contents note
  All reel-to-reel tapes have been duplicated onto cassette tapes, which serve as listening copies.
  - Reel-to-Reel Tapes
    - Roger Revelle, March 15, 1975 (Box 1)
    - E. Q. Daddario, March 19, 1975 (Box 1)
    - William T. Golden, April 2, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Ruth M. Davis, April 16, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Dael Wolfe, September 10, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Robert Q. Marston, September 24, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Dixy Lee Ray, October 7, 1975 (Box 1)
    - William D. Carey, October 22, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Lewis M. Branscomb, November 5, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Jeremy Stone, November 19, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Edward E. David, Jr., November 19, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Richard H. Bolt, January 21, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Don K. Price, January 28, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Leonard M. Rieser, February 4, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Athelstan Spilhaus, February 18, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Jesse D. Perkinson, March 3, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Betty M. Vetter, March 17, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Caryl P. Haskins, March 31, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Gordon J. F. MacDonald, September 15, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Hazel Henderson, September 22, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Dorothy S. Zinberg, October 6, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Arthur R. Miller, October 27, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Charles A. Mosher, November 10, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Alvin M. Weinberg, January 26, 1977 (Box 1)
    - John Walsh, February 9, 1977 (Box 1)
    - David E. Rogers, February 23, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Glenn T. Seaborg, March 23, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Garrett Hardin, April 6, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Betsy Ancker-Johnson, October 19, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Mike McCormack, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - Richard C. Atkinson, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - David A. Hamburg, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - Ormond M. Solandt, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - Eleanor Sheldon, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - Donald Kennedy, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - Sir William Hawthorne, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - Alice M. Riblin, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - Howard T. Markey, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
    - Jessica Tuchman Matthews, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
    - N. Bruce Hazzay, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
    - H. Bently Glass, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
    - Russel W. Peterson, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
    - A. Hunter Dupree, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
    - Jordan J. Baruch, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
    - Charles J. Hitch, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
    - Lucy Wilson Benson, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
    - Harold Leventhal, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
    - Arthur M. Bueche, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
    - Elmer B. Staats, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
    - Barbara J. Culliton, 1979-1980, [2 tapes] (Box 2)
    - Dorothy Nelmin, September 24, 1980 (Box 2)
    - David L. Bazelon, October 29, 1980 (Box 2)
    - E. Belvin Williams and Jenne K. Britell, November 5, 1980 (Box 2)
    - John M. Deutch, January 14, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Lili Horning, March 4, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Paul G. Rogers, April 1, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Marcel Roche, April 8, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Cassette Tapes
    - Philip Abelson, February 19, 1975 (Box 3)
    - D. L. Meadows, February 26, 1975 (Box 3)
    - E. Q. Daddario, March 19, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Ruth M. Davis, April 16, 1975 (Box 3)
    - William T. Golden, April 2, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Dael Wolfe, September 10, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Robert Q. Marston, September 24, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Dixy Lee Ray, October 7, 1975 (Box 3)
    - William D. Carey, October 22, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Lewis M. Branscomb, November 5, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Jeremy Stone, November 19, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Edward E. David, Jr., November 19, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Richard H. Bolt, January 21, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Don K. Price, January 28, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Leonard M. Rieser, February 4, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Athelstan Spilhaus, February 18, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Jesse D. Perkinson, March 3, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Betty M. Vetter, March 17, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Caryl P. Haskins, March 31, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Gordon J. F. MacDonald, September 15, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Hazel Henderson, September 22, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Dorothy S. Zinberg, October 6, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Arthur R. Miller, October 27, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Charles A. Mosher, November 10, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Alvin M. Weinberg, January 26, 1977 (Box 3)
    - John Walsh, February 9, 1977 (Box 3)
    - David E. Rogers, February 23, 1977 (Box 3)
    - Glenn T. Seaborg, March 23, 1977 (Box 3)
    - Garrett Hardin, April 6, 1977 (Box 3)
    - Betsy Ancker-Johnson, October 19, 1977 (Box 3)
    - Mike McCormack, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
    - Richard C. Atkinson, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
    - David A. Hamburg, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
    - Ormond M. Solandt, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
    - Eleanor Sheldon, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
    - Donald Kennedy, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
    - Sir William Hawthorne, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
    - Alice M. Riblin, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
    - Howard T. Markey, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Jessica Tuchman Matthews, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - N. Bruce Hazzay, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - H. Bently Glass, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Russel W. Peterson, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - A. Hunter Dupree, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Jordan J. Baruch, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Charles J. Hitch, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Ms. Lucy Wilson Benson, September 26, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Leventhal, October 24, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Mr. Bueche, October 31, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Elmer Staats, November 28, 1979 (Box 3)
    - George E. Brown, Jr., January 23, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Barbara J. Culliton, January 30, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Frank Press, February 27, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Rodney W. Nichols, March 19, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Dorothy Nelmin, September 24, 1980 (Box 3)
    - David L. Bazelon, October 29, 1980 (Box 3)
    - E. Belvin Williams and Jenne K. Britell, November 5, 1980 (Box 3)
    - John M. Deutch, January 14, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Lili Horning, March 4, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Paul G. Rogers, April 1, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Marcel Roche, April 8, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Robert N. Giaimo, October 28, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Chester E. Finn, Jr., November 11, 1981 (Box 3)
    - John Glenn, December 2, 1981 (Box 3)
    - John B. Slaughter, January 27, 1982 (Box 3)
    - George H. Keyworth II, February 3, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Donald S. Fredrickson, March 17, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Gerald Holton, March 31, 1982 (Box 3)
    - John D. Balderschwieler, April 14, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Elliot L. Richardson, April 21, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Matthew S. Meselson, October 26, 1982 (Box 3)
    - S. E. Toulmin, December 8, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Robert N. Butler, February 9, 1983 (Box 3)
    - James B. Wyngaarden, February 28, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Walter E. Massey, March 2, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Davie E. Bell, March 23, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Robert A. Frosch, April 6, 1983 (Box 3)
- Subject Files
  Arrangement note
  The files are arranged in reverse chronological order, beginning with the most recent files.
  - Predoctoral Fellows, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
  - Roundtable Speakers, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
  - Dr. David Bell, March 23, 1983-March 24, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Dr. D. Allan Bromley, March 16, 1983-March 17, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Robert Butler, February 9, 1983-February 10, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Robert Frosch, April 6, 1983-April 7, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Walter Massey, March 2, 1983-March 3, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Matthew Meselson, October 26, 1982-October 27, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Cheryl Payer, March 31, 1983-April 1, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Stephen Toulmin, December 8, 1982-December 9, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Dr. James Wyngaarden, February 23, 1983-February 24, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Round Table Speakers, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Foundations and Federal Agencies, undated (Box 4)
  - Round Table Pre-Doctoral Awards, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Possible Round Table Speakers, undated (Box 4)
  - Post-Doctoral Applicants Round Table, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Dr. John Baldeschwieler, Scientist in Residence, Spring 1982 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Chester Finn, November 11, 1982-November 12, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Donald Fredrickson, March 17, 1982-March 18, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Mr. Robert Giaimo, Esq., October 28, 1981-October 29, 1981 (Box 4)
  - The Hon. John Glenn, December 2, 1981-December 3, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Gerald Holton, March 31, 1982-April 1, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Dr. George Keyworth, February 3, 1982-February 4, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Dr. William Lowrance, October 14, 1981-October 15, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Mr. Elliot Richardson, April 21, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Dr. John Sloughter, January 27, 1982-January 28, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Provost's Roundtable [Financial Documents], 1981-1982, [2 folders] (Box 4)
  - Possible Future Speakers, undated (Box 4)
  - Round Table on Science and Public Affairs, 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - Round Table on Science and Public Affairs [Financial Documents], 1980-1981, [3 folders] (Box 4)
  - Round Table Predoctoral Fellows, 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - Dr. William Baker, April 22, 1981-April 23, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Judge David Bazelon, October 29, 1980-October 30, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Mr. W. Bowman Cutter, February 11, 1981-February 12, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Dr. John M. Deutch, January 14, 1981-January 15, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Lilli Hornig, March 4, 1981-March 5, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Joshua Lederberg, December 10, 1980-December 11, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Dorothy Nelkin, September 24, 1980-September 25, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Marcel Roche, April 8, 1981-April 9, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Mr. Paul M. Rogers, April 1, 1981-April 2, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Dr. E. Belvin Williams and Ms. Jenne Britell, November 5, 1980-November 6, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Round Table on Science and Public Affairs [Financial Documents], 1979-1980, [2 folders] (Box 4)
  - Misc. Round Table on Science and Public Affairs, 1979-1980, [2 folders] (Box 5)
  - Round Table Predoctoral Fellow, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - The Hon. Lucy W. Benson, September 26, 1979 (Box 5)
  - The Hon. George E. Brown, January 23, 1980-January 24, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Arthur Bueche, October 31, 1979-November 1, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Ms. Barbara Culliton, January 30, 1980-January 31, 1980 (Box 5)
  - The Hon. Harold Levanthal, October 24, 1979-October 25, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Rodney Nichols, March 19, 1980-March 20, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Frank Press, February 27, 1980 (Box 5)
  - The Hon. Elmer B. Staats, November 28, 1979-November 29, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Round Table - Miscellaneous, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Round Table [Financial Documents], 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Applicants for Round Table Predoctoral Fellowship, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Jordan J. Baruch, March 21, 1979-March 22, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Dr. A. H. Dupree, February 28, 1979-March 1, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Dr. H. Bentley Glass, January 24, 1979-January 25, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Dr. N. Bruce Hannay, November 8, 1978-November 9, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Charles J. Hitch, March 28, 1979-March 29, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Judge H. T. Markey, October 11, 1978-October 12, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Jessica T. Matthews, November 1, 1978-November 2, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Dr. R. W. Peterson, February 14, 1979-February 15, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - Round Table [Financial Documents], undated (Box 5)
  - Brochure, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - Predoctoral Fellowships in Science and Public Affairs, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Betsy Ancker-Johnson, October 19, 1977-October 20, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Richard C. Atkinson, November 30, 1977-December 1, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Donald R. Kennedy, March 8, 1978-March 9, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Dr. David Hamburg, January 25, 1978-January 26, 1978 (Box 5)
  - The Hon. Mike McCormack, November 9, 1977-November 10, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Sir. Wm. R. Hawthorne, April 5, 1978-April 6, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Alice M. Rivlin, April 11, 1978-April 12, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Eleanor B. Sheldon, March 1, 1978-March 2, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Omond M. Solandt, February 1, 1978-February 2, 1978 (Box 5)
  - The Hon. Ray Thornton, November 3, 1977-November 4, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Round Table on Science and Public Affairs-Miscellaneous, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - AAAS-AMER. Bar Ass'n Science and Law Conference, Duke Univ., 1976 (Box 5)
  - ABA-AAAS Conf. on Weather Modification-PUBLICATION, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Round Table [Financial Documents], 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Round Table on Science and Public Affairs Brochure, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Fellowships in Science and Public Affairs, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Applicants-NIMH Trainees Postdoct. Prog, 1977-1978 (Box 6)
  - Round Table-Fellowship Applicants, 1976-1977 (Box 6)
  - G. Hardin, April 6, 1977-April 7, 1977 (Box 6)
  - H. Henderson, September 22, 1976-September 23, 1976 (Box 6)
  - G. J. F. MacDonald, September 15, 1976-September 16, 1976 (Box 6)
  - A. R. Miller, October 27, 1976-October 28, 1976 (Box 6)
  - C. A. Mosher, November 10, 1976-November 11, 1976 (Box 6)
  - D. E. Rogers, February 23, 1977-February 24, 1977 (Box 6)
  - G. T. Seaborg, March 23, 1977-March 24, 1977 (Box 6)
  - J. Walsh, February 9, 1977-February 10, 1977 (Box 6)
  - A. M. Weinberg, January 26, 1977-January 27, 1977 (Box 6)
  - D. S. Zinberg, October 6, 1976-October 7, 1976 (Box 6)
  - Round Table, 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Dinners and Receptions, 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Luncheon Meeting on Round Table on Science and Public Affairs, November 4, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Luncheon Seminars, 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - R. H. Bolt, January 21, 1976-January 22, 1976 (Box 6)
  - L. M. Branscomb, November 5, 1975-November 6, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Wm. D. Carey, October 22, 1975-October 23, 1975 (Box 6)
  - E. E. David, Jr., December 3, 1975 (Box 6)
  - C. P. Haskins, March 31, 1976-April 1, 1976 (Box 6)
  - R. Q. Marston, September 24, 1975-September 25, 1975 (Box 6)
  - J. D. Perkinson, March 3, 1976-March 4, 1976 (Box 6)
  - Don Price, January 28, 1976-January 29, 1976 (Box 6)
  - Dixie L. Ray, October 7, 1975-October 8, 1975 (Box 6)
  - L. M. Rieser, February 4, 1976-February 5, 1976 (Box 6)
  - A. Spilhaus, February 18, 1976-February 19, 1976 (Box 6)
  - J. Stone, November 19, 1975-November 20, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Betty Vetter, March 17, 1976-March 18, 1976 (Box 6)
  - Dael Wolfle, September 10, 1975-September 11, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Round Table [Financial Documents], 1974-1975 (Box 6)
  - Luncheon Seminars, Spring 1975 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1974-1975 (Box 6)
  - Outline for a Round Table on Science and Public Affairs, undated (Box 6)
  - Proposed Symposium, Governors Inn, October 9, 1975-October 10, 1975 (Box 6)
  - P. H. Abelson, February 19, 1975-February 20, 1975 (Box 6)
  - E. Q. Daddario, March 19, 1975-March 20, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Ruth Davis, April 16, 1975-April 17, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Wm. T. Golden, April 2, 1975-April 3, 1975 (Box 6)
  - D. L. Meadows, February 26, 1975-February 27, 1975 (Box 6)
  - R. Revelle, March 5, 1975-March 6, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Round Table on Science and Public Affairs [Miscellaneous], undated (Box 6)
  - Round Table on Science and Public Affairs [Miscellaneous, from accession number A77-157], undated (Box 6)